## RAFAEL HENRIQUE DE ALMEIDA

Sluistraat 14, 5462CB, Veghel, NL

rafa.almeida.js@gmail.com

+310683417049

### **Professional Summary**

Experienced tech professional with vast knowledge in Javascript, Typescript, CSS and Pre-Processors (Less, Sass, SCSS), HTML, Vue.js and Angular. Currently working with SSR solutions with Nuxt.js (Vue.js), managing REST APIs with GraphQL for a Supermarket company. Already worked for big companies like KLM – Royal Dutch Airlines and GFT Group. Fluent English, Native Portuguese and Basic Dutch.

### Experience

## FRONT-END ENGINEER at JUMBO SUPERMARKTEN

October 2019 - Current

- Worked in the Selling Team, following Scrum/Agile methodologies with other 9 collaborators
- Migrated the legacy system to an SSR Nuxt application solution using Microservices and GraphQL
- Launched the Refund Project for customers, leading two other Engineers
- Engineered the consistency of different projects such as Promotions, Orders and Basket.

## **FRONT-END ENGINEER** at KLM – ROYAL DUTCH AIRLINES

October 2018 - October 2019

- Worked in the Sales Team, following Scrum/Agile methodologies with other 6 collaborators
- Developed the implementation of an Angular application using GraphQL
- Introduced the integration of the Design System created by the Design Team
- Monitored the stability of the customer journey on the sales process.

### SENIOR FRONT-END DEVELOPER at TECHIFIDE

September 2016 - October 2018

- Coordinated remotely a small developer's team on a London based startup
- Founded a new system for employee management using Angular 2.
- Offered support to the Node.is server when needed

#### **SENIOR FRONTEND DEVELOPER** at GFT GROUP

September 2015 - September 2016

- Launched the implementation of a new leasing system in thecity of Padova, IT
- Kept contact with managers and an International Italian team
- Implemented the migration of the old system to Angular v.1.6
- Secured the maintenance of the Cardini's website remotely

#### Leadership

## **FULL TIME VOLUNTEER** at BRAZIL PORTO ALEGRE SOUTH MISSION

April 2011 - April 2013

- Conducted and presided over meetings.
- Facilitated one on one training in communication skills.
- Presided conferences and language training.
- Travelled to train and motivate 16 full-time volunteers' representatives in the areas of communication and administration.
- Held a variety of leadership positions responsible for the health, safety, motivation, and results of other full-time volunteers.

#### Education

# **B.S Web Design and Development** at BRIGHAM YOUNG UNIVERSITY IDAHO

April 2011 - April 2021

Web Media Certificate at BRIGHAM YOUNG UNIVERSITY IDAHO 2018

## Languages

Native Portuguese speaker Fluent English speaker A1 Level Dutch Speaker

### **Technologies**

HTML, CSS, Javascript, Typescript, GRAPHQL, Vue.JS, NUXT.js, Angular, Webpack, GIT, Docker, AWS S3

### **Design Skills**

Illustrator, Photoshop, Premiere, After Effects, InDesign

#### Portfolio

https://github.com/rhenriquea

https://www.linkedin.com/in/rhenriquea/

https://www.behance.net/rhenriquea

https://rhenriquea.medium.com/